<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Torrenting on iHelio</title>
    <link>/tags/torrenting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Torrenting on iHelio</description>
    <image>
      <title>iHelio</title>
      <url>/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.142.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 16:17:15 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/torrenting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Build a home media server but automated</title>
      <link>/posts/2023/build-a-home-media-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 16:17:15 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2023/build-a-home-media-server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&#34;https://ihelio.today/archives/howtoroutetransmissiontovpncontainer&#34;&gt;Route transmission to VPN container&lt;/a&gt;, I talked about how to download contents via VPN tunnel so we can get rid of some troubles. But that is far from enough for us to build a home media server which should work as Netflix and Hulu to us. We shouldn&amp;rsquo;t bother with the torrent and subtitle search. Once we add a show to our watch list, everything should be set up automatically. I will introduce the tools and necessary setup for me to build a home media server in the following sections.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to route transmission to VPN container?</title>
      <link>/posts/2023/how-to-route-transmission-to-vpn-container/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 16:17:15 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/2023/how-to-route-transmission-to-vpn-container/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;intro&#34;&gt;Intro&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have a NAS at home, it feel bad if you don&amp;rsquo;t keep it running for something even if you don&amp;rsquo;t use it. It is the major backup to store the photos we shoot with our iphones. However, it is just basic use and hosting a media center with it sounds more cool. I used to use &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/haugene/docker-transmission-openvpn&#34;&gt;transmission-openvpn&lt;/a&gt; and it works perfectly, however, my VPN expires and I decided to use proton free tier. This is where things go south - I spent two days on it and I cannot get it work. When I am about to give up, I found a better approach for my purpose - running transmission and vpn in separate docker container and route transmission to vpn conatiner. It sounds a great idea in the first place given we should only do one job for each service - unix&amp;rsquo;s princinple.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
