<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Home Server on iHelio</title>
    <link>ihelio.today/categories/home-server/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home Server on iHelio</description>
    <image>
      <title>iHelio</title>
      <url>ihelio.today/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>ihelio.today/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.128.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 16:17:15 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="ihelio.today/categories/home-server/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Build a home media server but automated</title>
      <link>ihelio.today/posts/2023/build-a-home-media-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 16:17:15 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>ihelio.today/posts/2023/build-a-home-media-server/</guid>
      <description>Intro In Route transmission to VPN container, I talked about how to download contents via VPN tunnel so we can get rid of some troubles. But that is far from enough for us to build a home media server which should work as Netflix and Hulu to us. We shouldn&amp;rsquo;t bother with the torrent and subtitle search. Once we add a show to our watch list, everything should be set up automatically.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Expose NAS Services with Att Gateway</title>
      <link>ihelio.today/posts/2023/expose-nas-services-with-att-gateway/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 16:17:15 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>ihelio.today/posts/2023/expose-nas-services-with-att-gateway/</guid>
      <description>Recently I changed my ISP to ATT to try their fiber, and they gave me the bgw320 as the gateway for the Internet service. And I have trouble connecting to my Synology&amp;rsquo;s services like Jellyfin.
I suspect it has some conflicts with the network of these docker services running in Synology or the internet setup of Synology. Considering the configuration of docker network could be another rabbit hole, I didn&amp;rsquo;t go that route.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to route transmission to VPN container?</title>
      <link>ihelio.today/posts/2023/how-to-route-transmission-to-vpn-container/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Sep 2023 16:17:15 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>ihelio.today/posts/2023/how-to-route-transmission-to-vpn-container/</guid>
      <description>Intro When you have a NAS at home, it feel bad if you don&amp;rsquo;t keep it running for something even if you don&amp;rsquo;t use it. It is the major backup to store the photos we shoot with our iphones. However, it is just basic use and hosting a media center with it sounds more cool. I used to use transmission-openvpn and it works perfectly, however, my VPN expires and I decided to use proton free tier.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
